Barry S. Flickinger

1068 S Nancy LN | Gilbert, AZ 85296 | Cell: (480) 262-2744 | barry.flickinger@gmail.com

SYSTEMS ADMINISTRATOR

Solutions-focused, team oriented Information Technology Professional with over 20 years of experience. Proven proficiency in the design, configuration and implementation of multiple technologies and solutions. Seeking a position as a systems administrator with an organization that can utilize my talents and experience for mutual growth and success.

Areas of Expertise

- Citrix XenApp / XenDesktop Solutions using MCS and PVS
- Hyperconverged Technologies (Nutanix)
- Virtualization Technologies: VMWare, XenServer, KVM, Hyper-V
- Application Virtualization (App-V) and personalization (AppSense) in non-persistent environments.
- High Availability with Netscaler load balancing and Access Gateway.

Professional Experience

Blood Systems Inc — Scottsdale, AZ, 2005 to present **Senior Systems Administrator** (2012 to present) **Systems Administrator** (2004 to 2012)

Member of a team of individuals responsible for the planning, implementation and operations of over 300 Windows Servers for the support of the business, be it infrastructure or end user applications.

Participated on behalf of Blood Systems at Synergy 2013 with Thin Client Computing as guest speakers.

- VMWare ESXi 5.5 Administration and Support; P2V consolidation, SRM with synchronous replication and low RPO/RTO
- XenServer 5.6 Configuration, Administration and Support
- Netscaler 9.x/10.x Configuration, Administration and Support
- Citrix XenApp/XenDesktop 4.0 7.6 Principal Administrator; 2600 Concurrent Users
- Image automation and Quality Control with Microsoft MDT
- Citrix PVS Principal Administrator; Multiuser and Single User endpoints.
- Citrix XenClient Principal Administrator
- AppSense Principal Administrator
- Microsoft Server 2000 2012 R2 installation and configuration
- Active Directory Design, Administration and Support
- DNS, DHCP, DFS Design, Administration and Support
- WSUS Design, Administration and Support
- Exchange 5.5 2010 (current) Administration

Barry S. Flickinger

1068 S Nancy LN | Gilbert, AZ 85296 | Cell: (480) 262-2744 | barry.flickinger@gmail.com

- SQL 2000 2012 Installation and Support
- SAN Administration 3PAR, Nexsan, Nutanix, Nimble, HP Enclosures
- Anti-Virus Symantec and Sophos
- Backup and Protection CommVault, Veeam and Acronis.
- End-point scripting with vbScript and Powershell
- Disaster Recovery team member

Network Adept — Gilbert, AZ, 2002 to 2005 **Network Engineer/Systems Administrator** - Self Employed Contractor

As an independent, I undertook various commitments with local (Arizona) and out-of-state businesses providing contractual services as well as consultation. My primary focus was to supplement the workforce of said companies when needed with installation or troubleshooting expertise. I also engaged in many short to medium term contracts.

Contracts completed:

- DHL ITIL Audit 6 months (2004 to 2005)
- JCL Cisco Proxy Installation 2 months (2003)
- JCL Partner Medical Device VPN 1 month (2002)
- JCL Network Design and Implementation 2 months
- Harry and David Routing Design and Implementation 3 months (2002)

En Pointe Technologies — Portland, OR, 2001 to 2002 **Network Engineer/Systems Administrator**

En Pointe Technologies is a solutions provider that supplies products and services to medium and large enterprises, educational institutions and government agencies nationwide. As a Senior Engineer, my duties and responsibilities were:

- Project development and management.
- Sales support on network design and development of business proposals.
- Network and host security audits; penetration testing
- Operating Systems hardening and IDS implementation.
- Network troubleshooting with protocol analysers.
- Configuration and installation of a broad base of vendor networking equipment (Cisco, Nortel, Sonicwall, Packeteer).
- Server and desktop installation and support
- Application Installation and support

Additional IT Experience

Pacific Information Systems - Portland, OR

Network Engineer/Sysadmin

Barry S. Flickinger

1068 S Nancy LN | Gilbert, AZ 85296 | Cell: (480) 262-2744 | barry.flickinger@gmail.com

Metstream Communications - Portland, OR Convergent Communications - Portland, OR Enron Communications - Portland, OR Optec, Inc - Portland, OR Installer Network Engineer Network Engineer/Sysadmin Network Engineer Journeyman Structured Cabling

Education And Training

High School Graduate
US Army Fiber Optic Termination and Splicing Course
US Army Basic Installation Course
US Army Signal School (Secret Clearance)

Cisco Certified Network Associate CSCO10001188 Cisco Certified Design Associate CSCO10001188 Cisco Certified Network Professional CSCO1001188 Cisco Certified Design Professional CSCO1001188

Symantec Certified Specialist

MCSE NT 4.0, 2000, Current Certification under progress

State of Oregon JATC Journeyman, Limited Energy #236JLE (Lapsed)